(DRAMATIC MUSIC)
(UPBEAT MUSIC)
(TENSE MUSIC)
(RADIO CHIMES)
MAN (OVER RADIO): Hey, Bill.
I'm somewhere off 288 in Shelby.
Out about 10 miles past
the Armstrong spread.
I got half of moving beef.
Three trailers, engines runnin'.
BILL (OVER RADIO):
Why don't you wait for backup?
You ain't even
supposed to be on the clock.
I wait for you,
these boys will be in Texas.
BILL (OVER RADIO):
Okay, we'll notify local PD.
(CASE LATCHES)
(GUN LOADING AND COCKING)
(MAGAZINE SLIDES)
MAN: Here, here.
Move it.
Nice and...
Don't put them cows
in that trailer.
Put 'em in the second trailer.
No!
Hold that damn gate!
Come on now boy, use your head.
Oklahoma Department
of Agriculture.
I'm gonna need your boys
to stop doing what you're doing
right now.
No problem, officer.
We're just loading up
our livestock
'cause it's the best
time of day to do it.
Is it?
It's too damn hot in
the morning, hotter now.
Well I'm sure you got
some paperwork to confirm that.
Yes, sir.
Right here. No problem.
Hey, hey.
Stop right there.
Sure thing.
Boy, don't you be pissing
on my boots
and telling me it's raining.
- Now, sir...
- Get a move on.
(MAN GROANS)
No, no, no, no, no!
(MEN GRUNTING)
Stop! What are you doing?
(COW GROANS)
(THUD)
Stop!
(TENSE MUSIC)
Let's go to the back.
Let's go.
(COWS MOOING)
You're just south of 200.
Well.
That ain't no bear
or lion or pack of wolves.
Telling you, Frank, you ought to
take a look around these parts.
Things just ain't
adding up in the books.
You expect a few
critters to go missing.
Maverick here or there.
But this's been systematic.
FRANK: Charlie,
you don't have to call me up
every time you need
an inspection.
They got a self-inspect
system online now.
If I don't give you a call,
when would we get together
to shoot the shit?
That's right.
(CHUCKLES)
I don't know if
I ever told you...
I wasn't the original owner
of this ranch, Frank.
I inherited it from a feller
named George Fletcher.
There were rustlers,
outlaw Chickasaw,
rode onto the property
one night.
Any other night
it would have been fine.
George would have seen to it.
But he was in Fort Gibson
for work.
The only ones here,
his wife and son.
The rustlers seen
an opportunity,
made off with all his livestock.
Almost 400 head of cattle.
After... they killed
Mary Fletcher and her boy.
(SIGHS)
That's terrible, Charlie.
George buried his little family
out back there.
Came out to my place
the next morning,
asked me to look over the ranch.
Said if he didn't
never come back,
I should take on the deed.
Five years went by.
Fletcher was
just here one morning.
Almost standing
where we are now.
He set out to hunt down
all those that had paid a visit
to his place.
Told me he hung
each one of them at gunpoint.
Threw a rope up
over a branch and
watched the fight
get squeezed out of 'em.
Fletcher never
asked anybody for help.
He did what he had to do,
and when he was done,
he was done.
That was the last
I ever saw him.
Frontier justice.
Don't go getting any ideas,
Charlie.
Fight left me so long ago
I don't recall the taste.
I just want to go
into my house justified, Frank.
That's all.
Good to see you, Charlie.
(TRUCK ENGINE STARTS)
(TENSE MUSIC)
Oklahoma Department of
Agriculture confirmed concerns
that an uptick in livestock
theft is likely due to a single,
highly-organized criminal outfit
and should be considered
armed and dangerous.
They believe
the same gang was responsible
for an attack on a cattle
inspector last autumn
that's left him
crippled for life.
Anything else
I can get for you, hon?
Oh no, that'll do it, Carole.
Thank you very much.
That can't be you.
Frank Bennett?
Sylvia...
- Holy cow.
- You remember.
Yeah, of course, I remember.
How could I forget?
You want to sit down?
Oh, I ordered takeout.
Oh, okay.
I heard about Hannah.
I'm really sorry.
Yeah. Yeah, thank you.
It's...
We have all these dreams
and struggle
and then just like that...
It doesn't seem right.
Yeah.
But you, uh... moved away,
you got married?
You guys back visiting?
Uh, not you guys.
Just... just me.
Dad got ill
and needed help with the ranch.
Oh, I'm sorry to hear that.
About your dad.
You guys still got
the spread out by 288?
Yeah, exit at the truck stop.
Pa and I,
we're whipping it into shape.
It's a little overgrown, but...
- Yeah.
- Uh, here's your order, ma'am.
Oh, thank you.
You're back for good, or?
Well, as long as Dad needs me.
He always said you were
his best hand.
Did he really?
- He did.
- (CHUCKLES)
Well, tell him I said hello.
And give him my best.
I will.
I'm surprised
they let you in here.
(CHUCKLES) Well, they...
It's new ownership.
- Oh.
- They don't know about me.
They don't have like a mugshot
of you on the wall or something?
I hope not. I'm a cop, so...
Specifically,
I'm a... I'm a cow cop.
I mean, I'm at the...
livestock officer.
Not a cow cop.
(LAUGHS)
Fighting Frankie.
I haven't heard that
for a while.
Well, um...
I've got my ranch stuff and...
You look great.
So do you.
I don't normally do this,
but, uh... what the heck.
Anyway, if you're curious...
I'll call you.
Try to not get in any fights.
That's not who I am anymore.
Oh, really? That's too bad.
I kinda liked that guy.
(CHUCKLES) Fighting Frankie.
The kid ain't dead yet.
(VEHICLES WHOOSHING)
(COW MOOS)
(INDISTINCT AUCTIONEER VOICE)
BILL: Hey, partner.
Cup of Olive's finest.
And can you believe
Stone Camp's old ma
had his nurse bring him
out here?
Today?
Yeah, brought him up
from that assisted living place.
Thought it might be good
for him to be around the yards.
I mean, he did
love it here, but...
I'll go see him.
Yeah, well, I'm gonna leave that
to y'all, Frank. Too depressing.
Got to make a call home anyway.
(AUCTIONEERING)
(DOOR CLOSES)
(CHAIR SCRAPES)
How goes, partner?
I'm guessing you heard.
Yeah.
Cattle breeders got together.
They're going to the capitol.
Promise to fund a task force.
(SIGHS)
I don't give a shit
about that, Frank.
I can't
remember anything anyhow.
I shit myself this morning.
I was eating breakfast, and...
I knew what was happening,
but I just couldn't remember
what to do, you know,
what I...
what I was doing.
(SIGHS)
Fucking decorated
law enforcement agent,
crying like a baby.
Hey, it ain't your fault.
Four baldy calves
worth maybe 500 apiece.
Caved in my skull for...
two grand change.
We're gonna get the guys that
did this to you, Stone Camp.
We'll get 'em.
I won't quit till we do.
(TENSE MUSIC)
I got to turn in some papers.
All right?
You're in my prayers,
Stone Camp.
Now she's up in Glacier
working cows.
- All the way there?
- Yeah.
Jesus.
- And she doing real well. Mack.
- Frank.
Mack.
How's the sale so far?
Better than the last week,
so that's not bad.
Yeah? Good.
You know, I saw Rick
brought 20 head of blacks.
Uh-huh.
Said he would've brought more,
but 16 showed up missing.
Is that right?
16, huh?
Sounds like a trailer load.
It ain't right, Frank.
We'll do the best we can.
Fight 19th-century criminals
with 19th-century methods...
lynchings, frontier justice,
regulators like Tom.
You know they hung Tom,
don't you?
Just like they would today.
(DOOR OPENS)
You know, I ain't ever seen you
push a pencil so fast.
Bill, you mind my breakfast
sounds just fine right now.
The only thing open
is Dairy Queen.
How about that, uh, coffee shop
off of Highway 7, near Davis,
by the old Johansson spread?
That should be open late.
Come on. Frank,
it's in the middle of nowhere.
The Johansson ranch.
He had a daughter, right,
pretty thing? What was her name?
- Sylvia.
- Sylvia, right.
It seems the good ones leave
town first thing they can now.
♪ Struggle with morality ♪
♪ I don't write
the way I should ♪
♪ Deal the cards,
I'm in the game ♪
♪ And when it's time
to make my move ♪
Why is this joker
in such a hurry?
(HORN HONKS)
It's a two-lane highway, pal.
(HORN HONKS, TIRES SCREECHING)
What the crap?
♪ Got the perfect match ♪
(COOKING SIZZLES)
Here you go, sir.
Thank you.
Thank you, ma'am.
I beat you.
I lost ya.
Well, you know what,
just wanted to give you some
good news and some bad news,
and I'll give you
the good news first.
Jane's pregnant.
Oh.
You never let her up.
Ever since I've known Jane,
she's been pregnant.
What's that, three?
- Four.
Soon enough,
you'll have a herd of your own.
Yeah, well, I just might have
to auction off one or two.
The little buggers
are expensive.
Which, uh,
which leads me to the bad news.
I'm gonna put in
my notice, Frank.
Why, are you moving?
I don't know. I might have to.
It's hard, Frank.
I mean, 27 grand a year
and five mouths to feed,
and a sixth on the way.
And God forbid the government
gives us a living wage.
Christ, I don't even think
they give a shit anymore.
Too busy chasing drug dealers
and jihadists,
and, I don't know,
they don't give a good damn
about a bunch of rustlers.
I mean, hell, half the country
doesn't even know
that people
steal cattle anymore.
That fella
forget to pay his tab?
Happens all the time.
He hasn't left yet, if you
want me to go get your money.
There's no bother. He passes
through here every other week.
I'll get him on his next load.
Are you ready, gentlemen?
I'll just take
black coffee, ma'am.
Sure.
Coffee?
I thought you were starving.
How about you, honey?
Um, I guess I'll have one too.
You know what, Frank?
You're probably right.
We should just hit the road.
Suit yourselves.
I'm about ready
to close up anyhow.
You want those coffees to go?
- Yes, ma'am.
- That'd be great. Thanks.
No, order something.
I'll hang out while you eat.
No. No, Janie'll have leftovers
for me when I get home.
It's fine.
You know, I've thought about it.
Quitting?
Find that hard to believe,
you desperado.
I don't mind being out there
in the country on my own.
It's just going home
ain't no good.
Hard to find a woman who'll
take to that kind of life.
Finding more than one
in a lifetime is
probably next to impossible.
Well, who knows?
Maybe you'll get lucky.
Yeah.
All right.
Coffee's on me.
No, let me pay for this, Bill.
You got five mouths to feed.
Come on.
Would you let me buy my partner
one last cup of Joe, all right?
Thank you.
I got no cell service out here.
Does that line still work?
The phone company's still
charging me every month,
so it better.
Local calls only, though.
Yes, ma'am.
Let me get your change.
- No, no, you keep it.
- Yes, sir.
Careful on those roads.
Thank you.
Bill, you get rolling.
I'm going to make a phone call.
Nah, I'm in no hurry, pard.
Take your time.
(SIGHS)
(LINE RINGING)
VOICEMAIL: Hello,
you reached Sylvia.
I must be busy doing something,
but leave me a message
and I promise I'm going to get
back to you as soon as I can.
(BEEP)
Uh, Sylvia, it's Frank.
Uh, Frank Bennett
from the other night.
I was just, um,
wondering what you were doing
the next couple days,
if you're free, maybe,
you know, say tomorrow or...
It'd be great to see you again.
Um, well, my number's, uh,
480-509-0953.
So, I'll talk to you.
Son of a bitch.
Hey, Bill, you copy?
Pull over a bit, would you?
BILL: Sure thing, partner.
I could tell
you're already going to miss me.
(CHUCKLES)
You see those cattle trailers?
The ones we just passed? Yeah.
How about the one that nearly
ran us off the road ways back?
Yeah, so?
What do you suppose they're
doing this time of night?
I don't know, probably coming
back from the sale,
just like us.
Frank, what is it?
Nah, they're loading 'em
in the dark.
Shouldn't you be getting home?
No, no, no.
I see that look in your eye.
Go home to your wife and kids.
I'll let you know
in the morning.
No, sir.
You just lead the way, partner.
Everyone at home's
asleep anyway.
You got the balls for this?
There's three trailers.
I saw two guys.
- Probably more.
- All right.
Holy shit
That's quite an operation
Are you sure it ain't kosher?
Oh, no, there ain't
a big outfit like this
this side of the Ozarks.
Yeah. Pick off a cow here
and a couple there.
Yeah, 16 of Rick's best.
Scavenging all they could
till they got what they want
and the time was right.
(SIGHS)
Today. Ain't we the lucky ones?
Lucky us.
I don't see them heating up
any running irons.
That means they must've
rebranded them already.
Yeah, or they're taking 'em
someplace
where they won't have to.
You get signal out here?
No, I lost mine a way back.
Whoa, hold on.
Red truck.
FRANK: Oh, yeah.
That's the deadbeat
from the diner.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
BILL: Looks like
he's the one calling the shots.
(GROANS)
Well, there's a fifth one.
Yeah, I see him.
BILL: That big old bully boy.
MAN (IN DISTANCE):
Come on, now, boy, use your head
KURT: Hey, Thad, get to
heating up this running iron.
Philip, man should not live
on bread alone.
But perhaps
you should consider it.
Kurt, what's that line
in the bible about, uh...
he without sin
cast the first stone?
That's Jesus telling you
to shut the hell up
and stop sassing people.
Hey, Harris.
I don't know
what Peggy sees in you.
Harris, why'd we invite
this fat piece of shit?
It's good for morale.
He could eat that heifer
faster than he can load it.
- (CHUCKLES)
- Oh, you too now?
If you hadn't been late,
we'd be on the road by now.
Late, huh?
Which one of you geniuses
can spot a cow that's been bred
and know the difference
between weight by mass?
You need me and you know it.
Watch your mouth, kid.
It seems that we have
probable cause on this one.
Oh yeah.
The way I see it,
we got one choice
or another.
Uh-oh.
Get somewhere
where we can call this in,
wait for them
out by the highway.
Or?
We take them now.
(SIGHS)
Well, I could be sitting on my
ass at a freaking desk next week
and be pissed if we didn't.
Nah, boy.
You carrying?
No, I didn't think we were gonna
reenact the OK Corral
this morning.
Have I taught you anything?
Careful with her. She's my baby.
Will do.
You go left.
I'll go right.
Now make yourself useful
and go get my chew
out of the cab, would ya?
No, boy, you're still sassing,
I'm gonna call your mama.
I swear to God.
Every single day,
that boy's making me madder
than a mosquito in a
mannequin factory, sassin' me.
Oh, Philip's fat.
Philip's a blimp.
Look at Philip,
he's bigger than the cows.
(GATE LATCHES)
Hey, Kurt, hey.
What about them doggies?
Don't tell me we've stolen 'em
for nothing.
And what happens
at the weigh station?
Hauling 80,000 pounds,
it's too much, okay?
We're loaded up, let's roll.
Wait, we got
to rebrand 'em, though.
Pack it up.
We'll rebrand 'em down the road.
Hold it.
Hey.
Oklahoma Livestock.
No sudden moves, hey!
Oklahoma Department
of Agriculture.
Don't move.
Okay, mister.
Not a sound, you understand?
Yes, sir.
I ain't here to hurt you.
Now, let's go.
I want to see hands in the air.
Anyone reaches,
I won't hesitate.
Last I checked, it ain't illegal
to transport your own stock.
Your own stock, huh?
You have five
different brands in there.
I told you
we should have rebranded.
Shut your goddamn mouth.
Sir.
I need to see
some identification.
There ain't a cop
within 50 miles of here.
No one gives a shit
what you need.
Move!
I'm sorry, Kurt.
He came out of nowhere.
Philip, shut the fuck up!
Everybody just stop talking.
Department of Agriculture.
Agriculture.
Guessing this isn't your first
time getting arrested, Kurt.
Ain't my first rodeo.
Then I expect you to set
a good example for your boys.
Now everyone line up
against this truck, spread 'em.
You're under arrest
for rustling cows.
Frank.
We're missing one.
Jones, Harris.
(GUNSHOTS)
(COWS LOWING)
(GUNFIRE)
(DRAMATIC MUSIC)
That's gnarly.
Follow me. Let the dead
bury their own dead.
What the hell does that mean?
It means
there ain't no law out here
except what comes
out of the barrel of a gun.
Well there's five of us.
Shouldn't take us too long
to smoke him out.
We'll be looking all day.
It's what they want.
So what, we let 'em go?
No, we go.
We'll be in Texas before
they can call in the cavalry.
Okay.
What about this body?
We'll let the coyotes eat.
They didn't walk in.
Yeah, I'm on it.
Come on. Let's go.
Let's go. Come on.
(TRUCK ENGINE STARTING)
(HEAVY BREATHING)
(SOMBER MUSIC)
(GUNSHOT)
(DRAMATIC MUSIC)
Hey.
Hey!
I ain't picking up
no passengers.
Did you see
three trucks go by here?
No, sir.
I heard 'em, though.
Can you give me a ride?
It's important.
Well, Mama told me
not to pick up strangers.
Of course she's been dead
nearly 20 years.
Listen, mister,
I'm a livestock officer.
Those trucks are full of
stolen cows driven by rustlers.
I need to get out to the highway
and contact authorities
as soon as possible.
Rustlers, huh?
I heard they'll still hang a man
for that in Texas.
You give me a ride or not?
You say you're going
to the highway?
Well, officer, I'm going
in the other direction.
Did you hear what I just said?
I sure did.
I also heard a rat-a-tat-tat
about a half an hour ago, too.
Sometimes when there's popping
these parts,
there's valuable things
left behind.
All you'll find is my partner.
He's dead.
I'll take you to the highway,
no further.
Deal.
Pardon my mess.
My friends call me Aksel.
But I ain't got no friends
no more,
so you can call me
whatever you want to.
I'm Frank Bennett.
You get any service
out here, Aksel?
Service?
I'm off of that grid thing.
Don't much care for no authority
telling me what I can
and can't do neither.
You know anyone who lives
out here named Harris, or Jones?
Can't say I do.
Folks around here
mostly mind their own business.
Yeah, even if their business
is taking what isn't theirs.
(BRAKES SQUEAL)
There's a diner
just up the road.
Can you take me there?
I said to the highway
and no further.
You're on your own from here,
pilgrim.
Thanks for the ride.
Hey.
You weren't lying
about that friend of yours
that got himself shot up
back there, was you?
Go see for yourself,
or take me to that diner.
(TRUCK ENGINE REVVING)
(DRAMATIC MUSIC)
Hello?
(KNOCKS)
We ain't open
for a couple hours, sir.
You can't be back here.
Ma'am, I need to use your phone.
- You break down or something?
- I need to call the police.
For what?
I don't know you.
A police officer's been killed.
Some cattle rustlers
just east of here.
Now if you won't
let me use your phone,
I'll have to break in and do it
without your say-so.
I ain't got no phone.
There's no cell service
out here.
You can use the one
in the diner.
Okay.
- Thank you.
- Yeah, sure.
Thirsty?
Where's your truck?
Don't tell me it got stole too.
You run all the way here?
Bet you could use
a glass of water.
- (GUN COCKS)
- Hang it up.
And drop that carbine.
Ma'am, I don't want any trouble.
I'm not here to hurt you.
I said hang it up.
Or you'll be the one hurting.
I kill before and I will again,
so help me.
OPERATOR: 911,
what's your emergency?
Now the rifle.
Throw it over my way.
Pick the phone back up.
Pick it up.
Now dial this number.
982-581-2538.
(LINE RINGING)
It's ringing.
JONES: I told you not to be
calling while we're on the road.
Tell him it's Peggy.
It's Peggy.
JONES: What?
Tell him I need
to speak to Jones.
She needs to speak to Jones.
JONES: Who the fuck is this?
Kurt, it's Peggy,
for God's sakes.
Tell Jones to call me now.
The line went dead.
Hang it up. He'll call back.
You know, ma'am,
I'm kind of thirsty after all.
It's too bad.
(PHONE RINGING)
JONES: Who is this?
Jones?
Tell him who you are.
My name's Frank Bennett.
I'm a livestock officer.
Tell him what Peggy's doing.
Peggy's pointing
a shotgun at me.
Now ask him if he
wants me to kill you.
Do you want her to kill me?
He didn't say yes.
Didn't say no either.
Ask him how far they got.
Where are you?
JONES: Tell her
we're coming back.
They're coming back.
Rip the line out the wall.
In case you get the jump on me.
(GUNSHOT)
(LAUGHTER)
Come on, Peggy, think about it.
You're not going to get away
with this.
Whether it's me or someone else,
you'll get arrested,
if you're lucky.
Worse if you're not.
Worse? Huh?
Tell that to your
cop friend they wasted.
Yeah. They came by here
on their way out.
Said you might be coming.
Yeah, well, they were right.
They made his wife a widow.
Empty your pockets.
I see your hand make for a gun,
you won't have one no more.
Get over there by the sink.
Come on!
Put it in the drain.
Is Kurt your husband?
You don't get to make small talk
with me, mister.
Now, do as I told you.
If you were about to die,
and he left you a message,
wouldn't you want
to listen to it?
- Don't you talk about him.
- Why?
Because he never
asked you to marry him.
Because he was never there
for you, Peggy.
You don't owe Kurt anything.
You don't know
anything about me.
Oh, I know
he spent time in the pen.
Yes, sir. No, sir.
You're so smart.
Guess you know what kind
of a person that makes me, then.
Let's listen to something.
Hey, Frank,
I was hoping you'd call.
Tomorrow night's free, and
I can leave Dad for a couple.
Just give me a call
in the morning.
Good night.
Is that your wife or something?
My wife is dead.
(LAUGHS)
Don't expect me
to feel sorry for you.
Drop that phone in the drain.
Drop the phone.
Turn on the disposal.
Switch is on the left.
(GARBAGE DISPOSAL
WHIRRING AND GRINDING)
(GUNSHOT)
(GRUNTS)
(PANTING)
Ah!
Damn it.
(EERIE MUSIC)
(PANTING)
(GRUNTS)
You comin' in, Uncle Philip?
Oh, hell no,
I seen enough blood.
Suit yourself.
(COWS MOOING IN THE BACKGROUND)
(BELL JINGLES)
Peggy!
Son of a bitch punched me, Kurt.
Look at my face.
Goddamn it. Come here.
He did this to you?
He fucking did this to you?
I'm gonna fucking kill him.
Oh, yeah. Come on, baby.
Come on.
Man, we should probably scatter,
right?
He's probably called
the cops by now.
No fucking way he did.
I killed the phones.
I ain't stupid.
I'd have killed him, too,
if you'd have said so.
KURT: Ain't bad for a woman.
Hey, you think he took her car?
It don't run.
I'll go check
to see if it's there.
She just said
it don't fucking run.
I don't appreciate the way
you're talking to me.
How would you
like me to talk to you?
(GUNFIRE, SHATTERING)
What the fuck
do you think you're doing?
You shoot my place up?
I worked myself to the bone
to build this.
You'll pay for that.
Peggy, just calm down. Okay?
Don't tell me
to calm down again.
Look at my face.
This is 'cause of his
stupid-ass plan.
He's gonna buy me a new TV.
He will buy you a new TV.
Ain't that right, Jones?
What now, sir?
(TENSE MUSIC)
He's close.
Look, Jones,
we can get him this time.
He's not getting away.
Wrong.
He's got no truck, no cellphone,
no way out of here but to walk.
And it's several hours
to the next town.
Now, if we move fast
and we move now,
we can be in Amarillo by then.
Worst case, we drop the stock.
We sell the stock.
No matter what.
And what about Peggy?
She rides with me.
I need you to get those trucks
where they're intended.
Now look, I know
it's been a hell of a day.
I know that. Hell of a day.
But I know I can
rely on you, Kurt.
Right?
- Yeah.
Yeah.
Let's go.
Jesus Christ.
I thought you was that dead cop.
He ain't.
What do you mean he ain't?
Dearly departed.
Now how in the hell
is that possible?
(COWS MOOING IN THE BACKGROUND)
(PANTING) Shit.
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC)
I don't know what in the hell
I was thinkin'
havin' us throw in with Jones.
Shit, he's worse than you.
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC CONTINUES)
(COWS MOOING)
Aw, come on, now.
Son of a bitch!
Hey, we got a flat.
It's gonna take
about 15 or 20 to fix it.
We must have picked up a nail
or screw back at the diner.
Hey, pull over here
before that damn hill.
Yeah, you want us to turn back
and help them
or keep goin', Johnny?
Make sure
they get back on the road.
I ain't stoppin'.
Willie, this is Waylon.
We're comin' back to help you
as soon as we find a place
to turn around.
Get it fixed. Get back on track.
Johnny, don't worry about it.
I'll have it fixed
lickety-split.
Shit.
(TRUCK DOOR CLOSES)
Fuck, I can't do this now.
(INSECT BUZZES)
Okay, then.
We gotta wet that ram too.
(CHUCKLES)
That's what she said.
Hey, we gotta move, goddamn it.
I ain't never let none
of y'all down once, not once.
I don't deserve that.
I'm sorry, Philip.
When I think about what that
son of a bitch did to Peggy,
makes me crazy as hell.
I know.
How's she looking, big dog?
This thing's got me workin'
harder than an ugly stripper.
All right.
Hurry it up.
- We gotta get a move on.
- God damn.
- We don't know who's around.
- Freeze.
Drop the bar.
Put your hands on the truck.
Kurt, do what he says.
Don't even think about it.
Kurt.
Fuck!
(GUNSHOTS)
(GROANING)
(BULLET POPS)
Oh, boy.
Hey, hey, hey, you're all right.
Tell--tell Peggy I love her.
You got it, bubba.
I'll promise.
Just be quiet, boy. You're fine.
You're okay.
You're all right, boy.
You just take it easy now.
You just rest.
Everything's fine.
You just killed my nephew.
He killed himself.
Don't shoot me, mister.
I didn't do nothin'.
Nothing, huh?
I ought to gut you.
Go back there
and let them cows out.
You crazy?
Yeah.
Maybe I am.
(COWS MOOING)
Mister, you making me let
these cows go
is the same thing as killin' me.
Open it.
(TRUCK DOOR CREAKS)
Let's go. Let's go.
What you gonna do with 'em?
We're lettin' 'em go.
Free range.
(GUNSHOT)
They won't go far.
Anything happens to me,
Jones won't get them.
Willie, this is Waylon.
What's your mile marker?
Willie, come in.
Maybe they're almost done,
they can't hear the radio.
PHILIP: What now?
You answer some questions.
What the hell is this?
Stop the truck, Thad.
Stop the fucking truck.
Kill the engine.
Okay.
Who's that up there with Phil?
It's that cattle detective.
The cow cop?
Yeah.
(GUN COCKS)
What you gonna do with that?
I'm gonna do what we
should have done before.
Okay. Yeah. Um...
so you're gonna--you're gonna
do what we need to do,
and I'm gonna stay here,
help protect this load.
No.
You're my backup.
You know how to use
one of these things?
Yeah, I mean,
I had a BB gun once--
Jesus Christ.
Don't fucking aim
that gun at me.
- All right.
- Listen.
You squeeze that trigger,
and it goes bang.
You're on my six.
What's a six?
Fuck, Thad.
Get out of the truck
and follow me.
- Six.
- Come on, Thad!
Get out of the fucking truck.
I'm fucking coming!
Shh.
Where's he headed?
Jones,
where's he taking the stock?
It's over.
You might as well help yourself.
It ain't never over for Jones.
(GUNFIRE)
Phil? Phil, hey!
Phil, come over here!
Shut the fuck up.
(GASPING)
Get your shit together.
I need you in that truck
and driving off.
I'll shoot his ass
as soon as I see him.
I'm not going out there.
The fuck you're not!
I'm going to die.
- Fuck, now, get out!
- Oh, fuck!
(GUNSHOTS)
Oh, fuck. Fuck.
(GROANING) Ah, fuck!
God! They shot me,
Harris! I'm shot!
Ah! They blew my toes off!
(ENGINE TURNS OVER)
Move the truck, Thad!
(SOBBING)
(TRUCK DOOR SLAMS)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Got into some trouble
on the road?
This has nothing to do with you,
old-timer!
(MAN GRUNTING)
(GUNSHOTS FIRED)
(MEN GRUNTING)
(WATER SPLASHES)
(GRUNTING)
(BOTH GRUNTING)
Stay down.
It ain't worth it.
(PANTING)
(GRUNTING)
(WATER SPLASHES)
(PANTING)
(DRAMATIC MUSIC)
(GUNSHOT)
(GASPING)
(PANTING)
Did I kill that man?
Yeah.
You saved my life.
I thought you was full of shit
when I went back and seen
that friend of yours
all chewed up and spit out.
You sure picked
a hell of a fight.
Yeah.
Aksel, I'm gonna have
to deputize you,
whether you like it or not.
I don't like it.
Well, that's too bad.
Repeat after me.
I do solemnly swear...
that I will support and defend
the Constitution
of the United States
so help me God.
Oh, help me, God.
Good enough for me.
Wait, I need a badge.
No. It's not a requirement.
It is for me. I need a badge.
Well, I don't have a spare one.
Well, that one's okay.
What's up with him?
Oh, he ain't got
no fight left in him.
I got a gun and a badge,
motherfucker.
I drove past some fat man
hauling ass.
Was he with these fellas?
He won't get far.
Sure won't.
Where are you going now?
Where's your truck?
I don't remember.
Ah! Okay, I'm sorry!
I wager it's somewhere
around that corner.
I can drive you to it.
Aksel, can you hand me
that old smoke pole?
Hey.
You ever towed
a livestock train?
Yeah, once or twice.
You need anything else, partner?
Yeah, I'll tell you what.
You go find a phone.
I want you
to call the state police.
Tell 'em what's going on,
and tell 'em to meet us
at the diner.
You got it, pilgrim.
Don't touch that
or I'll kill you.
(PHONE BUZZING)
Is that Bill's phone?
Give it to me,
you piece of shit.
(OVER PHONE)
Where are you, honey?
I thought you'd be home by now.
I put the kids to sleep.
Abe was asking after you.
He cried for a bit.
I told him this was
your last night on the shift,
and you'd be there to put him
to bed from now on.
I know it was
a hard decision, honey,
but it was the right one for us,
your family.
Anyways, I love you.
Be safe, and we'll see you soon.
(OVER RADIO): Waylon,
this is Johnny. Where are you?
Waylon? Willie? Johnny?
The Highwaymen, huh?
Douchebags.
Yeah, this is Waylon.
We're headed east.
We're going back to the diner.
What the hell's going on, Thad?
No names on the radio.
Where are you, Waylon?
Is Willie back on the road?
No.
This is Frank Bennett,
the cow cop.
I'm driving now.
Where's Kurt?
(OVER RADIO) Well,
Kurt didn't want to be arrested,
so he's dead now.
Don't tell him nothing.
I knew I didn't like you.
Hey.
When I called you sir,
and you and your partner looked
at me all know-it-all and smug,
looked at me like
a screw in the yard.
You think you can pity me,
motherfucker?
You're gonna get yours
for what you did to my Kurt!
And I'm gonna find you!
(SCREAMS)
- Harris?
- (OVER RADIO) That you, Jones?
I'm guessing Harris
is the big fella, huh?
Nah, he didn't want
to get arrested, either.
So he's dead now, too.
What do you want, cattle cop?
No, Jones, I want what you want.
I figure you're headed
for the Texas border, huh?
No Brand State, right?
Between the two of us,
we got 100, 150,000 of beef.
It's quite a haul, Jones.
(OVER RADIO) 'Course,
it didn't quite work out
the way you wanted it, did it?
Your first load's drifting
all over Highway 288.
Your second's
moving the other direction.
So what's it gonna be, Jones?
You might make it
to the Texas border.
But there's gonna be
a whole bunch of boys there
waiting for you.
The way I see it,
you got one choice or another.
You can ditch your load now,
do your best to hide out
like a rat,
or you can come get the cows
I took from you.
Finish the job.
I'll be waiting at the diner.
We have to go back.
We have to go back
and take care of him.
Wait, wait,
be quiet, I'm thinking.
Yeah, well,
while you're thinking,
he's back there setting us up.
We stick to the plan.
I did my time.
I'm not doing it.
I will not go back to the jug.
You won't.
I will if that pig breathes.
He's bluffing.
What about the kid?
Yeah, if he's scared,
he'll squeal.
They all do.
You were always so good to Kurt.
He was my friend.
I'm all alone now, Jones.
I've seen the way
you look at me.
You're a real man.
Yeah.
And the truth is...
I don't wanna be alone.
Turn around now.
Don't think
I won't use this thing.
Use your brains.
Feelings will get you killed.
Did you not hear
what he did to my Kurt?
Turn around now!
Or I swear I'll kill you
and I'll drive myself.
(GUNSHOTS)
Damn it!
Turn around now!
Ain't none of you
got what it takes,
which is why you're all out
in the middle of the night
stealing cattle.
Relax.
I'll go back for the kid.
Let's go. Come on.
(GRUNTING)
I done like you asked.
But me and the 5-0 ain't got
a great history, so...
Hump the bumper.
Ain't gonna be here
for a couple hours.
I'll be done with you by then.
You want me to tie him up?
So I won't run away?
I'm gonna cuff him.
You got a firearm?
Just a revolver.
Take that.
Speaking of beef,
this psycho slaughtered
a couple head
when he was killing your friend.
You wouldn't mind
if one of those
came up missing, would you?
Might feed mine for a month.
Way I see it, the illegal
part's already been did.
You earned it.
(GRUNTING)
Slow down.
Why don't you speed up?
It's Philip.
Tell him to get in.
Get in.
Oh! Hey.
This ain't for me.
I'm going home.
Get in the truck.
I ain't dying for no cows.
I am D-O-N-E, done!
Get in, you fat fuck!
Yes, ma'am.
(TRUCK APPROACHES)
That murdering
shithead's gonna die.
If you give me the gun,
I can take care of it right now.
Just a sitting duck in there.
You'd shoot my whole place up,
wouldn't you?
That's my livelihood in there.
You'll make more money
from this truck and the other
than you will
in that goddamn dump!
That dump's all I got left.
Get out!
(TRUCK DOOR OPENS AND CLOSES)
Jones.
Frank.
What you smiling at?
Stand up.
I wouldn't, Peg.
Aksel. What the fuck
are you doing here?
Let's just say I ain't come
for bacon and eggs.
I swear...
I swear I'll kill you, too.
I got nothing to lose now.
As far as I'm concerned, Peggy,
you're just an accessory.
That ain't a life sentence.
You killed my Kurt!
Kurt killed himself.
That's what you're about to do.
He had a chance to live.
So do you.
I should have shot you before.
You've ruined me.
Hey, Jones,
they called the cops--
Don't anybody move.
I mean it.
Do it! Waste that motherfucker!
What now, Mr. Oklahoma
livestock agent?
Who am I kidding?
Pussy-ass bitch.
FRANK: Sit down, Jones.
I thought we might be able
to sort things out.
Man to man, you and me.
Peggy, how about some of that
delicious coffee of yours?
Go fuck yourself.
Thank you.
You married? You got a family?
Yeah.
I didn't think so.
Married man would've went home
instead of risking his life
out here,
chasing beef
that's probably covered
with a good insurance policy.
It ain't just a job for me.
We got that in common.
Not a lot of opportunities for
men like us, is there, Frank?
I have a decent life.
You call this decent?
- It's honorable.
- It's old-fashioned.
You might wanna get
that nose looked at, Peggy.
Sir.
The righteous are always
looking for righteousness.
But what they're really
looking for is order.
Evil has an order to it, too.
Sometimes, disorder
is the path to righteousness.
(HOT COFFEE SIZZLES)
(FRANK GRUNTS)
(YELPING)
(GUNSHOTS)
(SCREAMS)
(GLASS SHATTERS)
(GROANS)
(GUNSHOTS)
(SCREAMING)
You shot me!
I wasn't aiming at you, Peg.
I'm not trying to hurt you.
Don't make me kill you, darling.
Back! Back!
Let her go.
Jones, it's not worth it.
You killed my partner.
You put Stone Camp in a chair.
You'll pay for that.
Stay still!
Oklahoma.
It was Jones. He did it.
He beat that man without mercy!
(GUNSHOTS)
(SCREAMS)
(GROANING)
(PANTING)
Go ahead.
Run.
You all right?
Yeah, Aksel, I'm good.
Never shot a woman before.
Not sure I like it.
Oh, fuck.
Damn it, you son of a bitch.
Aksel, you got any more
of that lariat rope?
Depends on what you got in mind.
Something old-fashioned.
Hey.
Get up.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC)
Don't look at me.
Look straight ahead.
Sit on the bumper.
Put 'em on. Good and tight.
Give me that scatter gun.
Go tie this off, will ya?
Didn't you swear by some oath
to uphold the law?
I did, and I plan
on honoring it.
Make sure it's set real good.
Get up.
Step up there.
I'd prefer the bullet.
I'll give you a bullet.
You're not gonna like
where I put it.
Why don't you call the cops?
I promise I won't take off.
Think about yourself.
I'll think about all the people
that won't suffer
because of you.
Now get up there.
Put it around his neck.
He's makin' you an accessory.
You killed that man's partner.
Wait!
He thinks killing you is gonna
make that pain easier to bear.
That's what this is about?
What now?
Pull it real nice and tight.
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait!
(CHOKING)
- Wait!
- Aksel.
Don't you have some
slaughtered beef to collect?
Well, I do got somewhere to be.
Aksel.
I'm gonna forget you exist.
(PANTING)
Get it small, boss.
Call the cops.
They're already called.
Don't you move this truck!
Aksel!
This ain't very honorable
of you.
It's honest.
Just say when.
Wait. Wait, wait...
Please. Please. Please.
Please, wait. Please. Please.
When.
(ENGINE STARTS)
Wait, wait.
(GUNSHOT)
(GASPING)
Do you know how many people
you've hurt?
(SOMBER MUSIC)
Do you know
the damage you've done?
I ain't gonna kill you.
I won't throw
my life away for you.
I'll enter my house justified.
And not you
or anyone else will stop that.
(SIRENS WAILING)
May God have mercy on your soul.
(LIGHT MUSIC)
That's him.
Ma, I'll see you later.
Frank Bennett.
As I live and breathe.
I brought you some flowers.
You wanna come in?
I was wondering if you'd come.
I got tied up.
VOICEOVER:
Dear Mr. Frank Bennett,
we are writing this letter
of support to you.
We were victims of rustling
and lost everything.
We know about
the devastation this causes.
...courage in this day and age
is worth looking up to.
Good luck to you and we hope
you're through
this rough patch soon.
...to your noble actions
last summer,
we've been blessed
with a noticeable decline
in stolen livestock.
...to let you know you have
our appreciation and respect
for doing something
for the working man.
I'm writing this letter
on behalf of my husband,
Jethro Shelby.
We saw your story
on the local news.
We thank you, Mr. Bennett.
And if you ever need a place
to stay out West Texas way,
you give us a holler.